<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Billy Lynch</title><link>https://wlyn.ch/</link><description>Recent content on Billy Lynch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wlyn.ch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tekton and GKE Workload Identity</title><link>https://wlyn.ch/posts/gcp-tekton-workload-identity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wlyn.ch/posts/gcp-tekton-workload-identity/</guid><description>What is Workload Identity? When running a workload on Kubernetes, each Pod has an underlying service account identity that is used for interacting with the Kubernetes API and resources.
GCP has a similar concept of service accounts as a means for programs to authenticate to Google APIs. To make management of these secrets easier, GCP compute environments provide a mechanism called Application Default Credentials that allows users to map a VM to a particular service account.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Build Trigger Cookbook</title><link>https://wlyn.ch/posts/gcb-trigger-config-files/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 10:19:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wlyn.ch/posts/gcb-trigger-config-files/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/cloud-build/docs/running-builds/automate-builds&#34;&gt;Cloud Build (GCB) Triggers&lt;/a&gt; allows users to define triggers to automatically trigger builds on certain events with source code providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples to help get you started!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CS419 - Logging in to VMs via SSH</title><link>https://wlyn.ch/posts/2014-03-14-cs419-vm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wlyn.ch/posts/2014-03-14-cs419-vm/</guid><description>So logging in via X11 sucks. The problem with this is that you don&amp;rsquo;t know where the machine is and what address it is on. There is a way to programmatically find this information, but it relies on you having access to the .vmx file (which we don&amp;rsquo;t have). This feature is in development, but until then&amp;hellip;
Find your VM Your VM can exist on any ilab machine. Let&amp;rsquo;s find it.</description></item><item><title>Disabling MotD for PDSH</title><link>https://wlyn.ch/posts/2014-03-14-pdsh-disable-motd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wlyn.ch/posts/2014-03-14-pdsh-disable-motd/</guid><description>My friend V introduced me to an awesome tool called PDSH. One thing that really bothered me was when logging in to machines that had a message of the day, my screen would be flooded with messages, burying the information I needed.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to disable MotD from appearing in the output of PDSH. In your ~/.bashrc include:
export PDSH_SSH_ARGS_APPEND=&amp;quot;-oLogLevel=Error&amp;quot;</description></item><item><title>Introduction to the Unix shell</title><link>https://wlyn.ch/posts/2014-02-14-intro-to-unix-shell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wlyn.ch/posts/2014-02-14-intro-to-unix-shell/</guid><description>FAQ What&amp;rsquo;s a shell? A shell is a way to interact with your operating system via a text based system. This allows you to do useful things like fast searches and scripting. Since it is a minimal interface, it makes it great to use across network connections.
There are many types of shells including bash, csh, tcsh, and zsh.
Shell vs. Terminal People often ask what the difference between a shell and a terminal is.</description></item></channel></rss>